A Guide to the Philip S. Hench Walter Reed Yellow Fever Collection 1806-1995
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Philip S. Hench Walter Reed Yellow Fever Collection 1806-1995
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-1
67 linear feet; 154 boxes; Letters, maps, and reports-4 boxes: 43 cm x 53 cm x 8 cm; Letters, maps, newsclippings, and reports-90 boxes: 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm; Photos-25 boxes: 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm; Reprints-35 boxes: 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm
Transferred ca. 1982 from Alderman Library Special Collections, former accession number 8054. Originally gift of Mary Kahler Hench, 1966. Plus various additions: 1) Reed Family Additions and 2) Laura Wood Papers, transferred ca. 1982 from Alderman Library Special Collections; 3) P. Kahler Hench Additions, gift of P. Kahler Hench in 1988 and 1989; 4) P.S. Hench, HAM/TMC Additions, transferred from the Houston Academy of Medicine/Texas Medical College in 1991; and 5) Edward Hook Additions (James Carroll Papers, gift of Theodore Woodward to Edward Hook, 1995), separated from Edward Hook Papers, 2001.
Administrative Information
Access
No Restrictions
Biographical/Historical Information
Philip S. Hench (1896-1965) joined the Rheumatology staff of the Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minn. in 1921. Hench remained at the Mayo Clinic for the duration of his career, and won the 1950 Nobel prize for Physiology and Medicine with two other scientists for the discovery of cortisone. In addition to this scientific work, Hench pursued an interest in the conquest of yellow fever, with particular attention to the role of the United States Army Yellow Fever Commission of 1900-1901, headed by Army surgeon and bacteriologist Walter Reed. Hench undertook a thorough study of the facts and circumstances of the Commission's work, which had demonstrated that the mosquito Aedes Aegypti is the vector for the spread of yellow fever. From 1937 onwards for the next two and a half decades, Hench made thorough searches of innumerable archive collections, interviewed all of the survivors associated with the yellow fever experiments, and eventually amassed a substantial collection of letters and other original materials, all with a view toward publishing a definitive history of the events. Although his premature death prevented him from accomplishing his literary intentions, Hench remains a figure of critical importance to the history of yellow fever since the records of his meticulous research form the largest and most extensive archival collection on the yellow fever story and its interpretation as a public health victory.
Walter Reed (1851-1902) was an 1869 medical school graduate of the University of Virginia, the youngest student ever to have completed the University's medical curriculum. Subsequently, Reed enrolled at the Bellevue Hospital Medical College in Manhattan, where he received a second medical diploma in 1870. Reed interned at a number of hospitals in New York and worked for the Brooklyn Board of Health before joining the U.S. Army Medical Corps in 1875. Reed took assignments at various Army posts in the American West, including forts in the Arizona Territory, Nebraska, Dakota Territory, and Minnesota. In 1891 he completed advanced coursework in pathology and bacteriology in the Johns Hopkins University Hospital Pathology Laboratory, and in 1893 Reed joined the faculty of the Army Medical School in Washington, D.C., where he held the professorship of Bacteriology and Clinical Microscopy. He also became curator of the Army Medical Museum and joined the faculty of the Columbian University in Washington (later the George Washington University). His research interests as a bacteriologist ranged from erysipelas to cholera, typhoid, malaria, and yellow fever. In 1900 Surgeon General George Miller Sternberg appointed Reed the head of a scientific commission to Cuba to investigate the etiology of yellow fever. Human experiments undertaken by the Commission proved a mosquito vector for the disease and disproved infection from contaminated materials and air, then believed to be the only means of transmission, results which quickly and dramatically reversed the uncontrolled ascendancy of yellow fever epidemics world wide. Reed lived barely two years after the completion of the Commission's work, succumbing to appendicitis in November of 1902.
The name of Walter Reed has become synonymous with self-experimentation in medicine. Informed consent is also a hallmark of the Yellow Fever Commission. The Commission needed human subjects in order to test the mosquito theory because, at the time, no one knew of any animals susceptible to the disease. The commissioners agreed to experiment on themselves before requesting volunteers. Several Spanish immigrants participated in the experiments, but the majority of volunteers came from Lieutenant Albert E. Truby's Hospital Detachment at Camp Columbia. Governor-General Leonard Wood authorized Reed to offer the volunteers a $100 gold piece. To a poor Spanish immigrant or an underpaid army private, this was considerable incentive. Added to this was the likelihood of contracting yellow fever naturally during their assignment in Cuba, a point that Reed emphasized in the consent form. Reed said it would be better to contract yellow fever in a controlled environment where one could receive immediate medical attention from reputable physicians than to unexpectedly develop yellow fever in a remote camp where adequate care was unlikely. Even so, Reed stated the possibility that volunteers might die during the experiment. The members of the Yellow Fever Commission are considered the first advocates of informed consent because of their conscientious approach to human experimentation.
Scope and Content Information
The Philip S. Hench Walter Reed Yellow Fever Collection comprises letters, research notes, interview transcripts, photographs, negatives, reprints, and artifacts assembled by Mayo Clinic physician and scientist Philip S. Hench over a twenty-five-year period of research. The collection includes the largest extant compilations of original correspondence of Yellow Fever Commission members Walter Reed and Jesse William Lazear, and of U.S. Public Health Service physician and sanitarian Henry Rose Carter. Army Surgeon Jefferson Randolph Kean, who served as quartermaster for the Commission's experiments, and his first wife Louise Mason Young Kean are also well represented. Photostats of period materials in other archives, including official records and correspondence in the National Archives, supplement the original holdings and make this collection an extraordinarily complete record of all the activities surrounding the Commission's work. Additional papers in the collection include materials from Reed's first biographer, Howard Atwood Kelly, and from James Peabody of the New York State Biology Teachers' Association, concerning his efforts to commemorate the work of Reed. Also present are Hench's own extensive research and correspondence files, thoroughly documenting his efforts to verify the accuracy of the yellow fever story, to identify and collect information on all of the participants, and to identify, preserve, and memorialize the site of the Commission's experiments in Cuba. Evident as well is the close friendship which developed between Hench and various of the yellow-fever personalities, including volunteer John J. Moran, General Jefferson R. Kean, Brigadier General Albert E. Truby, and members of the Reed family. Special Note: Approximately 5,500 original documents with transcriptions and full-text search capability are available on line: http://yellowfever.lib.virginia.edu.
Arrangement
Series Description: The collection is organized into five principal series, as follows: 1) Jesse W. Lazear Series. 2) Henry Rose Carter Series. 3) Walter Reed Series, including Philip S. Hench's Reed-related collections and general correspondence. 4) Alphabetical Series, comprising Philip S. Hench's additional research materials and selected correspondence, arranged by personal name. 5) Truby-Kean-Hench Series, comprising selected correspondence of Philip S. Hench with Albert E. Truby and Jefferson Randolph Kean. Supplemental materials are organized by type, as follows: 1) Maps 2) Miscellany 3) Artifacts 4) Photographs 5) Negatives 6) Reprints 7) Oversize Materials Manuscript Additions are organized by accession, as follows: 1) P. S. Hench, HAM/TMC Additions 2) Reed Family Additions 3) P. Kahler Hench Additions 4) Laura Wood Papers 5) Edward Hook Additions (James Carroll Papers). Box 154, added in 2009, is arranged by date.
Contents List
- FAMILY TREE OF JESSE W. LAZEAR 1831, AMs (Box-folder 001-001)
  13 PAGES COPIED FROM THE ORIGINAL BY REDMOND JOHN GRACE
- STATEMENT BY SAMUEL PETTIGREW, MAYOR OF PITTSBURGH 1835/04/14, AMsS (Box-folder 001-002)
  GRANTS PROTECTION TO BENJAMIN PLOWDEN BARNEY, A FREE NEGRO FROM MARYLAND
- CONDUCT OF THE WAR 1863/02/28, PAMPHLETS (2) (Box-folder 001-003)
  SPEECH OF HON. JESSE LAZEAR OF PA. DELIVERED IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
- MARRIAGE CERTIFICATE OF WILLIAM L. LAZEAR AND CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1863/10/15, ADOCUMENT (Box-folder 001-004)
  WILLIAM LYONE LAZEAR AND CHARLOTTE CLAYLAND PETTIGREW
- DOCUMENT OF INDENTURE BETWEEN CHAUNCEY BROOKS AND JESSE LAZEAR 1866/05/24, AMs (Box-folder 001-005)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1866/12/22, ALS (Box-folder 001-006)
  CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR; ARTICLE FROM WAYNESBURY MESSENGER 1867/01/24, ALS, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 001-007)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1871/07/31, ALS (Box-folder 001-008)
  2 PAGES; CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1871/08/02, ALS (Box-folder 001-009)
  2 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1871/08/17, ALS (Box-folder 001-010)
  3 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- PURCHASE OF LAND FROM WINDSOR COMPANY BY JESSE W. LAZEAR 1871, DEED (Box-folder 001-011)
  IN ENVELOPE TO MABEL H. LAZEAR DATED 1900/10/08
- ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO MRS. W.L. LAZEAR 1871/ca., AENVELOPE (Box-folder 001-012)
  CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1872/05/24, ALS (Box-folder 001-013)
- BAPTISMAL CERTIFICATE OF CHARLES CLAYLAND LAZEAR 1874/04/13, ADOCUMENT (Box-folder 001-014)
  BROTHER OF JESSE W. LAZEAR
- JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR 1875/06/01, ALS (Box-folder 001-015)
  1 PAGE WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM L. LAZEAR TO JESSE W. LAZEAR 1876/09/07, ALS (Box-folder 001-016)
  2 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE
- LAST WILL AND TESTAMENT OF JESSE LAZEAR 1876/09/13, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-017)
  3 PAGES
- ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO REVEREND CHARLES R. HALE 1876/12/13, AENVELOPE (Box-folder 001-018)
- THE WASHINGTON COUNTY CENTENNIAL 1881, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-019)
  109 PAGES, PRESENTED TO JESSE W. LAZEAR BY BOYD CRUMWINE 1882/02/04
- ANNUAL REPORT OF THE PHI KAPPA PSI FRATERNITY 1886, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-020)
  14 PAGES
- DOCUMENT ATTESTING TO SALE OF TWO LOTS OF LAND BY CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR TO THOMAS C. LAZEAR 1886/09/17, TMs (Box-folder 001-021)
  4 PAGES
- CERTIFICATE OF GRADUATION FROM JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY AWARDED TO JESSE W. LAZEAR AND ACKNOWLEDGEMENT FOR A CONTRIBUTION MADE TO JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1887/04/30, DOCUMENTS (2) (Box-folder 001-022)
- REPORT ON JESSE W. LAZEAR'S GRADES AT JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1887/06/04, AMs (Box-folder 001-023)
- OBITUARIES OF WILLIAM ROBERT SWEITZER 1887/12, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (2) (Box-folder 001-024)
- ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO MRS. THOMAS R. SWEITZER 1888/02/06, AENVELOPE (Box-folder 001-025)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/05/15, ALS (Box-folder 001-026)
  3 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/05/18, ALS (Box-folder 001-027)
  14 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- TELEGRAM FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/05/28, TELEGRAM (Box-folder 001-028)
  WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- CARD ADMITTING JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CLASS IN PRACTICAL ANATOMY AT SUMMER SESSION, UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH 1890[05/29], PRINTED CARD (Box-folder 001-029)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/05/30, ALS (Box-folder 001-030)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/01, ALS (Box-folder 001-031)
  4 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/06, ALS (Box-folder 001-032)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/08, ALS (Box-folder 001-033)
  6 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/14, ALS (Box-folder 001-034)
  4 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE, FIRST PAGES MISSING; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/15, ALS (Box-folder 001-035)
  3 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/22, ALS (Box-folder 001-036)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/24, ALS (Box-folder 001-037)
  5 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/06/28, ALS (Box-folder 001-038)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/02, ALS (Box-folder 001-039)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/05, ALS (Box-folder 001-040)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/09, ALS (Box-folder 001-041)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/11, ALS (Box-folder 001-042)
- LETTER FROM DAVID HEPBURN TO JESSE W. LAZEAR 1890/07/12, APCS (Box-folder 001-043)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/15, ALS (Box-folder 001-044)
- CERTIFICATE OF MERIT, UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH, AWARDED TO JESSE W. LAZEAR 1890[07/17], DOCUMENTS (2) (Box-folder 001-045)
  AWARDED 17 JULY 1890. SEE LETTER OF SAME DATE, BOX 01, FOLDER 45.
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/17, ALS (Box-folder 001-046)
  3 PAGES; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/20, ALS (Box-folder 001-047)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/25, ALS (Box-folder 001-048)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/07/27, ALS (Box-folder 001-049)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/01, ALS (Box-folder 001-050)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/03, ALS (Box-folder 001-051)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/09, ALS (Box-folder 001-052)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/11, ALS (Box-folder 001-053)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/15, ALS (Box-folder 001-054)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/19/ca., ALS (Box-folder 001-055)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/21, ALS (Box-folder 001-056)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/08/24, ALS (Box-folder 001-057)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER [1890/08], ALS (Box-folder 001-058)
  3 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE, FRAGMENT OF LETTER; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/09/01, ALS (Box-folder 001-059)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/09/05, ALS (Box-folder 001-060)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/09/06, ALS (Box-folder 001-061)
  2 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1890/09/18, ALS (Box-folder 001-062)
- MEDICAL CERTIFICATION FOR JESSE W. LAZEAR NEW YORK COUNTY REGISTER OF PHYSICIANS AND SURGEONS 1892/08/09, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 001-063)
  NEW YORK COUNTY REGISTER OF PHYSICIANS AND SURGEONS
- JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1893/09/11, ALS (Box-folder 001-064)
- JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1893/09/12, ALS (Box-folder 001-065)
- TRANSCRIPT OF LETTERS FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR PRIMARILY TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1875-1900, TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-066)
  125 PAGES WITH INVENTORY; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- DIARY (PART ONE) OF MARTHA P. HOUSTON, MOTHER OF MABLE HOUSTON LAZEAR - EUROPEAN TRAVELS 1893-1895, DIARY (Box-folder 002-001)
- DIARY (PART TWO) OF MARTHA P. HOUSTON, MOTHER OF MABEL HOUSTON LAZEAR - EUROPEAN TRAVELS 1894-1895, DIARY (Box-folder 002-002)
- DIARY OF CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER, MOTHER OF JESSE W. LAZEAR 1894-1895, DIARY (Box-folder 002-003)
- DIARY OF CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER, MOTHER OF JESSE W. LAZEAR 1894-1895, TMs (4) (Box-folder 002-004)
  35 PAGES; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- TRINITY HALL 1894-1895, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 002-005)
  21 PAGES
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1895/06/28, ALS (Box-folder 002-006)
  [INCORRECTLY DATED 1894 ON LETTER] WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1895/06/30, ALS (Box-folder 002-007)
- ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1895/08/29, AENVELOPE (Box-folder 002-008)
- POSTCARD FROM H.S. HOOVER TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/04/10, APCS (Box-folder 002-009)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/05/26, ALS (Box-folder 002-010)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/06/14, ALS (Box-folder 002-011)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/06/21, ALS (Box-folder 002-012)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/06/28, ALS (Box-folder 002-013)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/07/02, ALS (Box-folder 002-014)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/07/14, ALS (Box-folder 002-015)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/07/16/, ALS (Box-folder 002-016)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/07/23, ALS (Box-folder 002-017)
  8 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/07/30, ALS (Box-folder 002-018)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/08/11, ALS (Box-folder 002-019)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO MABEL HOUSTON 1896/08/16, ALS (Box-folder 002-020)
  FRAGMENT WITH ENVELOPE
- UNIVERSITY CLUB MEMBERSHIP CERTIFICATE 1896/08/25, CERTIFICATE (Box-folder 002-021)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/08/25, ALS (Box-folder 002-022)
- MARRIAGE LICENSE AND CERTIFICATE 1896/09/03, DOCUMENT, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 002-023)
  JESSE W. LAZEAR AND MABEL HOUSTON
- WEDDING ANNOUNCEMENT 1896/09/08, PRINTED CARDS (2) (Box-folder 002-024)
- PHYSICIANS AND SURGEONS CERTIFICATE OF REGISTRATION 1896/10/12, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 002-025)
  ISSUED IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND TO JESSE W. LAZEAR
- FINAL SETTLEMENT OF ESTATE OF WILLIAM L. LAZEAR 1896/11/27, TMsS (Box-folder 002-026)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1896/12/18/ca., ALS (Box-folder 002-027)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/02/09, ALS (Box-folder 002-028)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/02/15, A;S (Box-folder 002-029)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/02/22, ALS (Box-folder 002-030)
  7 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/04/02, ALS (Box-folder 002-031)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/04/30, ALS (Box-folder 002-032)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/05/09, ALS (Box-folder 002-033)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/05/27, ALS (Box-folder 002-034)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/06/04, ALS (Box-folder 002-035)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/06/10, ALS (Box-folder 002-036)
  4 PAGES (FRAGMENT) WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/06/27, ALS (Box-folder 002-037)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/07/08, ALS (Box-folder 002-038)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/07/14, ALS (Box-folder 002-039)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/07/16, ALS (Box-folder 002-040)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/07/23, ALS (Box-folder 002-041)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/08/10, ALS (Box-folder 002-042)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/08/12, ALS (Box-folder 002-043)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/09/01, ALS (Box-folder 002-044)
  7 PAGES WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/09/05, ALS (Box-folder 002-045)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/09/09, ALS (Box-folder 002-046)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/09/16, ALS (Box-folder 002-047)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/09/21, ALS (Box-folder 002-048)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/10/08, ALS (Box-folder 002-049)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/11/02, ALS (Box-folder 002-050)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1897/ca., ALS (Box-folder 002-051)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/05/09, ALS (Box-folder 002-052)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/06/12, ALS (Box-folder 002-053)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/07/26, ALS (Box-folder 002-054)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/08/21, ALS (Box-folder 002-055)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/08/27, ALS (Box-folder 002-056)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/09/03, ALS (Box-folder 002-057)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/09/05, ALS (Box-folder 002-058)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/09/08, ALS (Box-folder 002-059)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/09/18, ALS (Box-folder 002-060)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/10/15, ALS (Box-folder 002-061)
  1 PAGE WITH ENVELOPE; CHARLOTTE C. LAZEAR
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1898/11/11, ALS (Box-folder 002-062)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/02/05, ALS (Box-folder 002-063)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/02/06, ALS (Box-folder 002-064)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/02/08, ALS (Box-folder 002-065)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/02/17, ALS (Box-folder 002-066)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/05/02, ALS (Box-folder 002-067)
  1 PAGE WITH ENVELOPE
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/06/12, ALS (Box-folder 002-068)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/06/16, ALS (Box-folder 002-069)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/06/25, ALS (Box-folder 002-070)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/07/09, ALS (Box-folder 002-071)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/09/06, ALS (Box-folder 002-072)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/09/21, ALS (Box-folder 002-073)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/09/30, ALS (Box-folder 002-074)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/10/08, ALS (Box-folder 002-075)
- LETTER FROM JESSE W. LAZEAR TO CHARLOTTE C. SWEITZER 1899/10/16, ALS (Box-folder 002-076)